Guide to the Davies/Scroggie Collection of Yukon Correspondence and Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Davies/Scroggie collection of Yukon correspondence and records
1903-1913
1906-1913
WA MSS S-2751
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.3
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, receipts and other records that document business and commerce in the vicinity of Dawson, Yukon Territory, in the early twentieth century. The bulk of the material spans the dates 1906 to 1913, with one letter from 1903. The Bank of British North America correspondence documents the activity of the Dawson branch and includes correspondence from grocers, wholesalers, miners, jewelers, and insurance and real estate agents. Landahl's Emporium correspondence documents the wholesale and retail purchase and sale of goods. The Canadian Department of the Interior Records consist of reimbursement receipts and receipts for mining permit fees, documenting the survey and inspection of mining and timber resources in Yukon Territory.
Davies, Grant, 1947-
Davies, Carole-Ann Scroggie, 1949-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carole-Ann Scroggie Davies and Grant Davies, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, receipts and other records that document business and commerce in the vicinity of Dawson, Yukon Territory in the early twentieth century. The bulk of the material spans the dates 1906 to 1913, with one letter from 1903. The Bank of British North America correspondence documents the activity of the Dawson branch and includes correspondence from grocers, wholesalers, miners, jewelers, and insurance and real estate agents. Landahl's Emporium correspondence documents the wholesale and retail purchase and sale of goods. The Department of the Interior Records consist of reimbursement receipts and receipts for mining permit fees, documenting the survey and inspection of mining and timber resources in Yukon Territory.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Bank of British North America Correspondence, 1903-1913. II. Landahl's Emporium Correspondence, 1907-1913. III. Canadian Department of the Interior Records, 1910.
Bankers -- Yukon; Banks and banking -- Yukon; Forests and forestry -- Yukon; General stores -- Yukon; Merchants -- Yukon; Mines and mineral resources -- Yukon; Natural resources -- Yukon; Real property -- Yukon; Timber -- Yukon; Dawson (Yukon) -- Commerce; Dawson (Yukon) -- Economic conditions; Yukon -- Commerce; Yukon -- Economic conditions; Bankers -- Yukon -- 20th Century; Merchants -- Yukon -- 20th Century; Davies, Carole-Ann Scroggie, 1949-; Davies, Grant, 1947-; Bank of British North America; Canada. Department of the Interior; Landahl's Emporium
- Bank of British North America Correspondence, 1903-1913; Series I; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Incoming and Outgoing.
  - Incoming
    Organized under three headings by region: North America, Europe, and Unidentified and Unsorted Locations.
    - North America
      Arranged alphabetically by location.
      - Ab-Bon (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Scope and Contents
        Aberdeen, Washington
        Arthabaska, Quebec
        Bear Creek, Yukon Territory
        Bellingham, Washington
        Bon (14 Below District), Yukon Territory
      - Bonanza, Yukon Territory, 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2-9)
      - Bos-Chi, 1906-1911 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Boston, Massachusetts
        Boyd, Oregon
        Bunker Hill, Yukon Territory
        Calgary, Alberta
        Carbondale, Pennsylvania
        Caribou
        Chicago, Illinois
      - Coa-Dav, 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Coal Creek, Yukon Territory
        Cobalt, Ontario
        Davenport, Washington
      - Dawson, 1902-1912 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
      - Dawson (continued), 1906-1912 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Day-Det, 1906-1911 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        Dayton, Ohio
        Duvall, Washington
        Denver, Colorado
        Detroit, Michigan
      - Dominion, Yukon Territory, 1906-1913 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Dun-Eld, 1906-1913 (Box 2, Folder 19)
        Duncan Creek, Yukon Territory
        Eagle, Alaska
        Edmonton, Alberta
        Eldorado
      - Fai-Fle, 1907-1913 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        Fairbanks, Alaska
        Fifty, Alaska
        Forty Mile, Yukon Territory
        Fort William, Ontario
        Flescher's Road House
      - Fra-Gol, 1906-1913 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        Franklin, Alaska
        Glen Boyle, Yukon Territory
        Glacier Trail, Yukon Territory
        Gold Bottom, Yukon Territory
        Gold Run, Yukon Territory
      - Gra-Hav, 1906-1913 (Box 2, Folder 22-25)
        Grand Forks, Yukon Territory
        Granville, Yukon Territory
        Haverhill, Massachusetts
      - Hig-Mai, 1906-1913 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        Highet Creek, Yukon Territory
        Hunker, Yukon Territory
        Indian River, Yukon Territory
        Jackson
        Jackwade, Alaska
        London, Alaska
        Limwood, Massachusetts
        Los Angeles, California
        Lovett Gulch
        Maiden Lane, New York
      - Mayo, Yukon Territory, 1907-1913 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Mid-Min, 1907-1913 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        Middletown, New York
        Miller House, Alaska
        Minto Bridge, Yukon Territory
      - Mon-Mt., 1907-1911 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        Montesario, Washington
        Mt. Vernon, Washington
        Mt. Vernon, New York
        Montreal, Quebec
      - New York, New York, 1909-1912 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Nor-Par, 1907-1912 (Box 3, Folder 31)
        North Fork [Klondike River], Yukon Territory
        Oakland, California
        Ottawa, Ontario
        Paris, Yukon Territory
      - Pen-Qua, 1907-1913 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        Penticton, British Columbia
        Pierreville, Quebec
        Portland, Oregon
        Preston, Ontario
        Prince Rupert, British Columbia
        Quartz Creek, Yukon Territory
      - Ren-Sai, 1907-1913 (Box 3, Folder 33)
        Reno, Nevada
        Regina, Saskatchewan
        Renton, Washington
        Rider Creek Camp
        Rochester, New York
        Saint Louis, Missouri
      - San Francisco, California, 1907-1913 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Seattle, Washington, 1906-1913 (Box 3, Folder 35-39)
      - Selkirk (Fort), Yukon Territory, 1907-1913 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Spr-Ste, 1907-1913 (Box 3, Folder 41)
        Spring City, Pennsylvania
        Steele Creek, Alaska
        Stewart River, Yukon Territory
      - Sulphur Creek, Yukon Territory, 1907-1912 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Sum-Tac, 1903-1913 (Box 4, Folder 43)
        Summerland, British Columbia
        Summit Road House
        Livingston Creek, Yukon Territory
        Tacoma, Washington
      - Toronto, Ontario, 1906-1913 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Twe-Val, 1907-1910 (Box 4, Folder 45)
        Twelve Mile Power Plant
        Valdez, Alaska
      - Vancouver, British Columbia, 1906-1913 (Box 4, Folder 46-48)
      - Vic-Wind, 1906-1913 (Box 4, Folder 49)
        Victoria, British Columbia
        Walla Walla, Washington
        Walkers Fork, Alaska
        Washington, D.C.
        Windsor, Ontario
      - Winn-Whi, 1906-1913 (Box 4, Folder 50)
        Winnipeg, Manitoba
        Whitehorse, Yukon Territory
    - Europe
      - Eng-Sco, 1907-1913 (Box 4, Folder 51)
        England
        Isle of Patos, Greece
        Italy
        Scotland
    - Unidentified and Unsorted Locations
      - Unidentified locations, 1906-1913 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Unsorted correspondence, 1907-1913 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Rost, Peter and Elizabeth (Various Locations), 1907-1911 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Outgoing
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1907-1910 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - 1911-1913 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Landahl's Emporium Correspondence, 1907-1913; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Incoming
    - Bon-Dee, 1908-1913 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      Bonanza
      Circle City, Alaska
      Dawson City, Yukon Territory
      Deerfield, Massachusetts
    - Fai-Mon, 1907-1912 (Box 6, Folder 58)
      Forty Mile
      Granville
      London
      Minneapolis
    - Qua-Sea, 1908-1912 (Box 6, Folder 59)
      San Francisco, California
      Seattle, Washington
    - She-Twe, 1908-1913 (Box 6, Folder 60)
      Sheridan, Washington
      Toronto, Ontario
      Twelve Mile
    - Van-Whi, 1907-1913 (Box 6, Folder 61)
      Vancouver, British Columbia
      White Horse
      Winnipeg
      White Pass & Yukon Route
  - Outgoing
    Arranged in reverse chronological order.
    - 1909-1913 (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Canadian Department of the Interior Records, 1910; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Reimbursements, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Mining Recorder Receipts, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 64)